翻译，压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/LAUj-TQpn-A
原视频发布日期：20190703
我是Rocket Lab空间系统的总工程师Grant Bonin
My name is Grant Bonin and the chief engineer of space systems here at Rocket Lab.
在过去 一般而言 一个空间任务往往是
The canonical way that people have done space missions in the past
(客户)去从一个供应商买有效载荷
has been they go out they buy a payload from one vendor.
而去另一个供应商买卫星平台 或者说总线
To buy a satellite platform, a bus from another vendor.
然后再去第三家购买发射服务
Then buy a launch from a third party.
或有时通过中间人或经纪人
Or sometimes through an intermediary or a broker.
它就像放养一群猫
and it's like herding cats.
你必须把所有事都放到一个流程里
You've got to pull all that together into a program.
这是非常昂贵 非常困难的
It was very expensive, very difficult.
你就无法专注做你该做的了
And you lose focus on the thing that actually matters.
而提供这种发射和卫星平台的一站式服务
By being a one-stop shop for launch and a satellite platform
我们可以真正帮助客户只专注于他们赚钱的那部分流程 也就是他们的有效载荷
we can really help customers hyper focus on the part of their program that makes the money which is their payload.
我们可以给人们提供整套解决方案
We can take care of pretty much the entire solution for people
这将极大地简化他们前往太空的流程
and that simplifies dramatically how they go to procure space
电子运载火箭的三级 也就是kick stage 让人印象深刻
The third stage of the kick stage of the Electron launch vehicle is a really impressive vehicle all by itself.
我们下一步要做的是增加发电能力
The next logical step for us is to incorporate power generation capabilities
同时在其他方面也进行增强 使之成为一颗全功能的卫星
and augmented in a few other ways to turn it into a fully featured satellite
这是相对简单的一步 也一直在Rocket Lab的总体规划中
and that's a relatively straightforward step that had always been part of the master plan for Rocket Lab.
而现在 通过把kick stage改进为光子上面级
So right now by evolving our kick stage into Photon
我们可以为给客户按需定制
we can offer really a huge amount of configurability for customers depending on what they need.
光子上面级可以搭载多种不同的仪器和有效载荷
Photon can carry a wide range of different instruments and payloads.
可以是地球遥感相机
Anything from telescopes that can take pictures of the earth.
气象监测设备
Weather monitoring equipment.
甚至是天基互联网
Even to do space-based internet access to people.
因此光子上面级提供了很多不同的子系统和配置
And in support of that Photon offers a wide range of different subsystems and configurations.
总体上来说就是耐辐射的航电材料和高精度姿态控制
But in general it gives radiation tolerant avionics extremely high precision attitude control.
航天器需要有足够的发电能力和推进系统
Our spacecraft pointing high-powered generation capability and great propulsion system
还有把数据
and overall the ability to communicate that data
把来自仪器或载荷的数据高速发回给地球的能力
that an instrument or payload generates down to the earth at very high rate.
可以说这就是人们几十年来一直在讨论的实用敏捷响应航天器
People've been talking about operationally responsive space for decades and now it's actually here.